Finding Aid for St. Alban's Episcopal Church, Highland Park, Mich., Records 1907-1976
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
St. Alban's Episcopal Church, Highland Park, Mich., Records 1907-19761940-1976
St. Alban's Episcopal Church (Highland Park, Mich.)
2 linear feet and 4 oversize volumes
Church established in 1908 and disbanded in 1976 because of declining membership. Vestry meeting minutes, 1909-1976; registry of church services, 1943-1976; volume containing photographs, clippings, and published materials, 1925-1943 (scattered dates); and registers (1907-1976) of baptisms, burials, marriages, and communicants
9415 Ba 2
Bentley Historical Library University of Michigan
The record group was donated by the Episcopal Church, Diocese of Michigan (Donor No. 1059 ) in June 1993 and March 2002.
The record group is open for research.
Beyond scattered details found in the records of St. Alban's Episcopal Church, historical information about this church is unfortunately lacking. St. Alban's was started in 1908 by the Rev. William F. Faber. The member initially held services in a doctor's office, then moved in 1912 to a location on Glendale Avenue in Higland Park, Michigan, where eventually in 1918 a chapel was constructed. Because of declining membership, the church disbanded in 1976, holding its last service on January 25.
The records of St. Alban's Episcopal Church contain information on the secular workings of the church. The three main series are: Vestry Meeting Minutes (1909-1976), Registers of Church Services (1943-1976), and Registers of baptisms, burials, marriages, and communicants (1907-1976).
Subjects:
Episcopal Church--Michigan--Highland Park.; Highland Park (Mich.)--Church history.; St. Alban's Episcopal Church (Highland Park, Mich.); Registers of births, etc.--Michigan--Highland Park.
Subjects - Visual Material:
Churches--Michigan--Highland Park.; Episcopal Church--Michigan--Highland Park.; Highland Park (Mich.)--Churches.
Genre/Form:
Photographs.
- Vestry Meeting Minutes, 1909-1976
  Vestry Meeting Minutes (1909-1922, 1931-1947, 1963-1976) contains minutes of the vestry, church members who managed the secular affairs of the church.
  - 1909-1913 (Box 1)
  - 1913-1922 (Box 1)
  - 1931-1938 (Box 1)
  - 1939-1947 (Box 1)
  - 1963-1970 (Box 1)
  - 1970-1976 (Box 1)
- Registers of Church Services, 1943-1976
  Registry of Church Services (1943-1976) contains the listings of all church services, including what services were performed, location, attendance, number of communions, offerings, celebrant or officiate, preacher, server, and memoranda.
  - 1943-1953 (Box 2)
  - 1953-1959 (Box 2)
  - 1959-1970 (Box 2)
  - 1970-1974 (Box 2)
  - 1974-1976 (Box 2)
- Registers of baptisms, burials, marriages, communicants
  - Comprensive volume No.1,, 1907-1958, (contains baptisms, 1907-1916; confirmations, 1908-1915; burials, 1909-1914 and 1956-1958; marriages, 1907-1919) (Volume 1)
  - Comprensive volume No. 2, 1920-1030 (Volume 2)
    (includes contains baptisms, 1920-1931; confirmations, 1920-1931; burials, 1920-1930; marriages, 1920-1929)
  - Comprensive volume No. 3, 1930-1975 (Volume 3)
    (contains baptisms, 1930-1967; confirmations, 1932-1975; burials, 1930-1956)
  - Register of baptisms, 1968-1975 (Box 2)
  - Register of burials, 1958-1976 (Box 2)
  - Register of marriages, 1927-1938 (Box 2)
  - Register of marriages, 1938-1945 (Box 2)
  - Register of marriages, 1945-1949 (Box 2)
  - Register of marriages, 1949-1974 (Volume 4)
    (oversize volume no. 4)
- Miscellaneous
  - Scrapbook/photograph album ca. 1925-1940 (Box 2)
    (contains scattered photographs of the church building and church groups, and published miscellanea)
  - Lists of church members, Sunday school teachers, students, and other church related associates, 1941-1947 (Box 2)